A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Administration, Program and Policy, RG 3 FA112
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Administration, Program and Policy, 1
  - Humanities, 1914-1972; 911; 5 document cases
    - Program and Policy - Cultures, National and International, 1933-1952, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Program and Policy - Cultures, National and International, 1933-1952, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Program and Policy - Cultures, National and International - Report, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Report: Informal Discussion, The Betterment of International Relations on a Cultural Level; April 1, 1939
    - Program and Policy - Cultures, National and International - Report, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Report: Humanities Conference, Cultures, National and International, Reviews and Summaries; January 15, 1943
    - Program and Policy - Education, 1949-1953 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Program and Policy - Far Eastern Studies, 1931-1951 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Program and Policy - Far Eastern Studies, 1931-1951 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Program and Policy - Far Eastern Studies - Reports - Pro Fes-1 - Pro Fes-4, 1930-1955 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Pro Fes-1 DR 428: A Brief Summary of the Conferences of Trustees and Officers at Princeton; Jerome D. Greene; Memorandum on Humanistic Studies in Eastern Asia (Copies filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-22); October 1930
      Pro Fes-2 DR 469: Humanities - Far Eastern Studies, Extract from the Rockefeller Foundation Agenda for Special Meeting; April 11, 1933
      Pro Fes-3 DR 445: Interim Report of Activities of the Rockefeller Foundation During 1933 Trustees Meeting (Copies filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-24 and under divisions); December 13, 1933
      Pro Fes-4 DR 491: New Program in the Humanities, Trustees' Meeting (Copies filed RG 3.1 911 Pro-7); April 10, 1935
    - Program and Policy - Far Eastern Studies - Reports - Pro Fes-5- Pro Fes-8, 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      Pro Fes-5 DR 500: Humanities, Extract from Director's Report on Program Trustees' Meeting (Copy filed RG 3.1 911 Pro-10); December 11, 1935
      Pro Fes-6: David H. Stevens; The Humanities, Draft on Humanities Program for the President's Review (Copy filed RG 3.1 911 Pro-10); December 1936
      Pro Fes-7: David H. Stevens; Notes for the President's Review and Annual Report (Copy filed RG 3.1 911 Pro-11); 1937
      Pro Fes-8: David H. Stevens; Memorandum on the Far Eastern Grants of the Humanities Division of the Rockefeller Foundation; February 14, 1938
    - Program and Policy - Far Eastern Studies - Reports - Pro Fes-9, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      Pro Fes-9: Charles Burton Fahs; Possible Lines of Humanities Programs Extensions in Asia; October 1955
    - Program and Policy - Liberal Education, 1941-1955 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Program and Policy - Liberal Education, 1941-1955 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Program and Policy - Liberal Education, 1941-1955 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Program and Policy - Liberal Education - Reports - Pro Lib Ed-1, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      Pro Lib Ed-1: Memorandum on Aids to Undergraduate College in the United States; January 18, 1943
    - Program and Policy - Liberal Education - Reports - Pro Lib Ed-2, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      Pro Lib Ed-2: Fred B. Millett; The State of the Humanities, An Informal Survey (Department of English, Wesleyan University); 1943
    - Program and Policy - Liberal Education - Reports - Pro Lib Ed-2a, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      Pro Lib Ed-2a: Fred B. Millett; A Survey of Programs and Personnel (Working draft in outline for inquiries into the organization of Humanities in a liberal arts college); 1942
    - Program and Policy - Libraries, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Program and Policy - Libraries, 1950-1956 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Program and Policy - Literature, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 0041a)
    - Program and Policy - Museums, 1919, 1937, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Program and Policy - Museums, 1919, 1937, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Program and Policy - Museums - Reports - Pro Mus-1, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      Pro Mus-1: John Marshall; The Rockefeller Boards and Museums, A Resume of Rockefeller Foundation and General Education Board Programs; December 9, 1955
    - Program and Policy - Music, 1948-1958 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Program and Policy - Music, 1948-1958 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Program and Policy - Music, 1948-1958 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Program and Policy - Music - Report - Pro Musi-1, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      Pro Musi-1: Charles Burton Fahs; The Role of the Rockefeller Foundation in International Affairs in the Musical Arts; October 1959
    - Program and Policy - Public Opinion, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Program and Policy - Radio and Motion Pictures, 1914-1963, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Program and Policy - Radio and Motion Pictures, 1914-1963, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Program and Policy - Radio and Motion Pictures - Reports - Pro Rmp-1 - Pro Rmp-2, 1949, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 52)
      Pro Rmp-1: John Marshall; Evaluation of Development since 1900 in Mass Communications with Special Reference to Radio, Address given at 10th Anniversary of Rocky Mountain Radio Council; October 14, 1949
      Pro Rmp 2: Joan Ogden; The Rockefeller Foundation and Film (Office of Publication); 1964
    - Program and Policy - Trustee Committee on Review, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Program and Policy - Trustee Committee on Review, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Publicity and Publications, 1911-1973; 912; 4 document cases
    Correspondence, memoranda, and reports concerning the formulation of publication and publicity policies. Includes documentation of the beginning of the Office of Publications and copies of Rockefeller Foundation publications.
    - BUL-G - Bulletin, 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - BUL-G - General Bulletin, 1920-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - BUL-G - General Bulletin, 1920-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - BUL-Q - Quarterly Bulletin, 1927-1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - BUL-Q - Quarterly Bulletin, 1927-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - BUL-Q - Quarterly Bulletin, 1927-1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - BUL-Q - Quarterly Bulletin, 1927-1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - BUL-Q - Quarterly Bulletin, 1927-1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - BUL-Q - Quarterly Bulletin, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - BUL-Q - Quarterly Bulletin, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - BUL-2 - Index to Quarterly Bulletin, 1927-1932 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - IHB-2 - International Health Board Publications Quarterly Bulletin, 1920-1927 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - IHB-2 - International Health Board Publications Quarterly Bulletin, 1920-1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - IHB-2 - International Health Board Publications Quarterly Bulletin, 1920-1927 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - PAM - Purpose and Program - Pamphlets, 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      General note
      See 912 PAM-8 Box 3 Folder 27
    - PAM-1 - A Brief History of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1913-1950 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - PAM-2 - General Education Board, Charter and By-Laws, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - PAM-3 - The Rockefeller Foundation - Charter, Constitution and By-Laws, 1916-1950 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - PAM-4 - The Rockefeller Foundation Directory of Officers and Field Staff, 1934-1950 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - PAM-5 - Fellowship Information - General Education Board, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - PAM-5 - Fellowship Information - International Health Division, 1930-1948 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - PAM-5 - Fellowship Information - Rockefeller Foundation, 1927-1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - PAM-6 - The Rockefeller Foundation Memorandum for Staff Members, 1927-1931 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - PAM-7 - Philanthropic Boards - Established by John D. Rockefeller, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - PAR-T - Purpose and Program - International Health Board, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - PAM-8 - Purpose and Program - General Education Board, 1941, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - PAM-8 - Purpose and Program - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1916-1973 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - PAM-9 - Summary From Annual Report - Rockefeller Sanitary Commission, 1911, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - PAM-10 - "Skill, Knowledge, and Judgement" - Address by C. I. Barnard, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - PRES - President's Review, 1917-1928 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - PRES - President's Review, 1917-1928 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Publications, 1915-1919 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Publications, 1942-1948 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Not Used (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Publications - Thirty-Year Review, 1942-1949 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Publications Office, 1919-1963 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Publications Office, 1919-1963 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Publicity, 1913-1948 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Publicity, 1913-1948 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - ROCK-1 - Rockefeller Foundation Press Releases, 1913-1921 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - ROCK-1 - Rockefeller Foundation Press Releases, 1913-1921 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - ROCK-1 - Rockefeller Foundation Press Releases, 1913-1921 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Division of Studies, 1923-1926; 913; 1 document case
    Spotty correspondence and memoranda regarding the creation, in 1923, of this division to be responsible for the administration of projects outside the field of the then existing departments of the Rockefeller Foundation.
    - Program and Policy, 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Service Departments, 1917-1950; 914; 1 document case
    Correspondence and memoranda concerning the administration of support services such as accounting, computer services, filing, purchasing, and statistical analysis.
    - Purchasing Department, 1917-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Purchasing Department, 1917-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Statistical Department, 1929-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 1913-1958; 915; 4 document cases
    Correspondence, memoranda and reports concerning the development and administration of programs in agriculture and in natural sciences. The agricultural interests were combined with the Natural Sciences Division in 1946. A new program called Natural Sciences and Agriculture was formed in 1951. The natural sciences aspect was terminated in 1955. It was resurrected in 1959 when two new programs were formed: Agricultural Sciences; and Medical and Natural Sciences.
    SEE ALSO: Series 900 General Program and Policy, Program and Policy, Food SEE ALSO: Series 923 Agriculture SEE ALSO: Series 924 Medical and Natural Sciences
    - Program and Policy, 1913-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Program and Policy, 1913-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Program and Policy, 1913-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Program and Policy, 1913-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Program and Policy, 1913-1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-1 - Pro-5a, 1916-1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Pro-1 DR 75: Natural Sciences, Application from the Committee of One Hundred on Scientific Research of the American Association for the Advancement of Science; May 24, 1916
      Pro-2: Appropriations, Pledges, Authorizations and Estimates, The Natural Sciences; October 15, 1930
      Pro-3 DR 486: Natural Sciences, Extract from Report of Committee on Appraisal Presented at Trustees Meeting (complete Report filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-27); December 11, 1934
      Pro-3a: Warren Weaver; The Aims of Science Teaching; 1932
      Pro-3b: Warren Weaver; The Benefits from Science, Science and Foundation Program, The Proposed Program; January 27, 1933
      Pro-4: The Natural Sciences, History of Policies and Project Policy Proposed Program; 1933
      Pro-5 DR 469: Natural Sciences, Past Program and Proposed Future Program, Extract from Agenda of Special Meeting of Trustees (complete agenda filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-23); April 11, 1933
      Pro-5a: Warren Weaver; The Science of Man; November 29, 1933
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-6 - Pro-9, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Pro-6 DR 475: The Natural and Medical Sciences Cooperative Program, Extract from Interim Report presented at Trustees Meeting (Complete Report filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-24); December 13, 1933
      Pro-7: Warren Weaver; Natural Sciences, The Program in Vital Processes, Used in Connection with Preparation Material on Appraisal; October 24, 1934
      Pro-7a: Warren Weaver; Progress Report, The Natural Sciences, Used in Connection with Preparation of Material for Committee on Appraisal; February 14, 1934
      Pro-7b: Warren Weaver; The Natural Sciences, Report to the Committee of Review, Appraisal and Program; March 5, 1934
      Pro-7c: Alan Gregg and Warren Weaver; Past Applications in the Field of Vital Processes (used in connection with preparation of material for Committee on Appraisal); March 6, 1934
      Pro-7d: Warren Weaver; The Program in Experimental Biology, Relationship of Medical Sciences and Natural Sciences; December 3, 1934
      Pro-8a: Warren Weaver; Relation Between Medical Sciences and Natural Sciences Programs; October 2, 1935
      Pro-9 DR 500: The Natural Science Budget, Extract from Director's Report on Program (complete Report filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-28); December 11, 1935
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-10 - Pro-16, 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Pro-10: Warren Weaver; Progress Report, The Natural Science Program in Experimental Biology; May 16, 1936
      Pro-11: Warren Weaver; How Do Applications Arise? Draft of statement prepared for Raymond B. Fosdick; April 25, 1936
      Pro-12: Warren Weaver; The Case for Small Projects; November 5, 1936
      Pro-13: Natural Sciences, Extract from Statement of Program presented at Special Trustee Conference (complete report filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-30)
      Pro-13a: Warren Weaver; Program and Administration; October 1, 1937
      Pro-14: Warren Weaver; Definition of Natural Sciences Program; November 29, 1937
      Pro-15: Raymond B. Fosdick; Relations between the Medical Sciences and Natural Sciences Statement of Policy Presented at Executive Session of Trustees, November 30, 1937; December 10, 1937
      Pro-16: Some Promising Fields for Foundation Activity, compiled by officers of the Rockefeller Foundation; 1938
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-17, Volume 1, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Pro-17, Vol 1: Activities in the Natural Sciences, The Rockefeller Foundation, Volume 1; 1938
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-17, Volume 2, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Pro-17, Vol 2: Activities in the Natural Sciences, The Rockefeller Foundation, Volume 2; 1938
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-18, 1933-1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Pro-18: Natural Sciences Appropriations; 1933-1946
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-19, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Pro-19: Report of the Committee of Review, Appraisal and Advice, The Rockefeller Foundation Division of Natural Sciences (copy filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-45m); May 1939
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-20 - Pro-24, 1942-1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Pro-20: Analysis of Program in Relation to Changing World Conditions Preliminary Divisional Statement used at Officers Conference (complete Report field RG 3.1 900 Pro-35); November 1944
      Pro-21: Natural Science Notes on Officers Techniques (includes 2 copies of document and letter of explanation to John D. Rockefeller); January 11, 1946
      Pro-21a: Warren Weaver; "How Do You Do, Dr. X?" Techniques in Handling Callers; August 1952
      Pro-22: Natural Sciences, Excerpt from Plans for the Future Work of the Rockefeller Foundation (Used as a Basis for Discussion at Trustees' Meeting April 4, 1945) (Complete Report filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-40a); November 1944
      Pro-23: Warren Weaver; Statement of Natural Science Program; November 27, 1946
      Pro-23a: Warren Weaver; Natural Science Program, Geographical (and Functional) Distribution; January 14, 1947
      Pro-24: Geographical Distribution of the Rockefeller Foundation Program in Natural Sciences in the United States from 1932-1948, Trustees' Actions; 1949
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-25 - Pro-29a, 1948-1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Pro-25: Warren Weaver; Natural Sciences Program, General Summary; December 3, 1948
      Pro-25a: Warren Weaver; Charts Used in Historical Presentation of Natural Sciences Program Trustees' Meeting (No record was kept of Mr. Weaver's oral presentation); April 6, 1949
      Pro-26: Warren Weaver; The Program in the Natural Sciences Trustees' Confidential Report; March 1950
      Pro-26a: The Chemistry of the Living Cell (including report of Rockefeller Foundation aid in field of enzymology) Excerpt from Trustee Confidential Bulletin; April 1950
      Pro-27: The Mother Substance of Life (including summary of Medical Sciences-Natural Sciences support of nucleic-acid research) Excerpt from Trustees' Confidential Monthly Report; April 1, 1951
      Pro-28: Warren Weaver; Classification of Natural Sciences Activities; May 18, 1951
      Pro-28a: Classification List (revised), Division of Natural Sciences and Agriculture; Summer 1953
      Pro-29: Warren Weaver; Natural Science Program (originally written July 19, 1951); September 27, 1951
      Pro-29a: Warren Weaver; Natural Sciences and Agriculture Program, Experimental Biology in the United States and "Liquidating Grants"; January 16, 1953
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro-30 - Pro-32, 1953-1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Pro-30: Charts Used by Warren Weaver in Discussion of Natural Sciences and Agriculture Program, Trustees Meeting (there is no written record of Mr. Weaver's presentation)
      Pro-31: Warren Weaver; The Program of the Division of Natural Sciences and Agriculture (revised August 27, 1953); August 27, 1953
      Pro-32: Warren Weaver; A Quarter Century in the Natural Sciences (from the President's Review); 1958
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro Rev-1, Volume 1, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Pro Rev-1, Vol. 1: Activities in the Natural Sciences, Volume I; 1933-1938
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro Rev-1, Volume 2, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Pro Rev-1, Vol. 2: Activities in the Natural Sciences, The Rockefeller Foundation, Volume 2 (copy filed 915, Pro-17 Vol 2); 1933-1938
    - Program and Policy - Reports - Pro Rev-2, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Pro Rev-2: Report of the Committee of Review, Appraisal and Advice, The Rockefeller Foundation, Division of Natural Sciences (copies filed 915 Pro-19); 1939
    - Program and Policy - Agriculture, 1927-1955 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Program and Policy - Agriculture, 1927-1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Program and Policy - Agriculture, 1927-1955 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Program and Policy - Reports - P&P Agr-1, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      P&P Agr-1: Alan Greg; A Division of Agricultural Science; 1929
    - Program and Policy - Reports - P&P Agr-2 - P&P Agr-5, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      P&P Agr-2: Advisory Committee for Agricultural Activities; The World Food Problem, Agriculture and the Rockefeller Foundation; June 21, 1951
      P&P Agr-3: Warren Weaver; Population and Food (originally written July 17, 1949) (copy filed 900 Population); July 8, 1953
      P&P Agr-4: J. G. Harrar and Warren Weaver; Research on Rice; October 21, 1954
      P&P Agr-5: The Rockefeller Foundation, "The International Development of RF Operations in Agriculture"; March 4, 1954
    - Program and Policy - Budget, 1935-1955 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Program and Policy - Budget, 1935-1955 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Program and Policy - Committee of Review, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Program and Policy - Committee of Review - A-Z, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Program and Policy - Consultants, 1943-1946 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Program and Policy - Earth Science, 1933-1940 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Program and Policy - Forestry, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Program and Policy - Forestry - Report - Pro For-1, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Pro For-1: I. W. Bailey and H. A. Spoehr; Report Based Upon Survey of Research in Biological Sciences Fundamental to Forestry; June 1927
    - Program and Policy - Genetics - Reports - Pro Gen-1 - Pro Gen-3, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      Pro Gen-1: Summary of Rockefeller Foundation Program in Genetics; November 24, 1948
      Pro Gen-2: Summary of Natural Sciences Program in Genetics; April 1, 1949
      Pro Gen-3: The Study of Heredity and Variation (including report on Rockefeller Foundation aid in field of genetics), Excerpt from Trustees' Confidential Monthly Report; March 1, 1950
    - Program and Policy - Human Biology, 1924-1928 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Program and Policy - Physics, 1939-1950 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Program and Policy - Physics, 1939-1950 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Program and Policy - Physics - Report - Pro Phys-1, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      Pro Phys-1: Warren Weaver; The Physics of Atomic Structure, approved by Executive Committee January 16, 1947; December 8, 1946
    - Program and Policy - Psychology, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Program and Policy - Vital Processes, 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Program and Policy - Vital Processes - Report - Pro Vit Proc-1, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      Pro Vit Proc-1: Warren Weaver (director); The Program in Vital Processes, The Natural Sciences, The Rockefeller Foundation; October 24, 1934
    - Program and Policy - Vital Processes - Subcommittee on Appraisal, February-December 1934 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Program and Policy - Vital Processes - Subcommittee on Appraisal, February-December 1934 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Staff, 1935-1955 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Staff, 1935-1955 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Counsel, 1923-1977; 916; 1 document case
    Correspondence and memoranda relating to appointments and the administration of the Rockefeller Foundation's counsel service.
    - Counsel, 1923-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Counsel, 1923-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Counsel, 1923-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2.1)
    - Counsel - Power of Attorney, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Travel, 1926-1967; 917; 1 document case
    Correspondence, memoranda and directives concerning arrangements, allowances and authorizations for the travel of Rockefeller Foundation staff.
    - Travel, 1926-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Travel, 1926-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Travel - Airplanes, 1927-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Travel - Airplanes, 1927-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Travel - Automobiles, 1928-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Travel - Automobiles, 1928-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Immigration, 1938-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Immigration, 1938-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Immigration, 1938-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Education Board, 1916-1982; 918; 1 document case
    Correspondence, memoranda and reports relating to the General Education Board.
    SEE ALSO: Separate GEB collection
    - General Education Board, 1916-1955, 1972, 1974, 1976, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Education Board, 1916-1955, 1972, 1974, 1976, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Education Board - Reports - GEB-1 - GEB-4, 1922-1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      GEB-1 DR 261: General Education Board - Relation to Rockefeller Foundation Conference on Division of Fields of Work (copy filed RG 3.1 900 Pro-11); May 24, 1922
      GEB-2 DR 332: Organization and Establishment of Various Rockefeller Boards Including record of gifts as outlined in correspondence between John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (copy filed RG 3.1 900 Org-17); April 9 and May 18, 1926
      GEB-2a: Trevor Arnett; General Education Boards, Comments on its Objects, Work and Organization; December 30, 1926
      GEB-2b: Committee on Reorganization of the General Education Board Vol. I Confidential; December 20, 1926
      GEB-2c: Trevor Arnett; Proposed reorganization of the General Education Board, Confidential; November 7, 1928
      GEB-3: Reorganization of the Rockefeller Boards, Items re: General Education Board collected from Minutes and Office Conferences (Complete Report filed RG 3.1 900 Org-30); 1927-1930